Guide to the Fredericka Martin Papers ALBA.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Medical Personnel: Biographical Files and Correspondence, 1936-1988
  - Cuba: Odio Pérez, Eduardo, 1968-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cuba: Solis, Oscar: Correspondence, undated, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Czechoslovakia: Doctors and Nurses, undated, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Czechoslovakia: Edenhoffer, Aurora, undated, 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Czechoslovakia: Glaznerová Kohnova, Alice, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Czechoslovakia: Kalisová, Marie, undated, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Czechoslovakia: Kalisová, Marie, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Czechoslovakia: Katz, Otto (a.k.a. André Simon), undated, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Czechoslovakia: Kisch, Bendrick, undated, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Czechoslovakia: Kriegel, Frantisek, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Czechoslovakia: Vesela, Vlasta, undated, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Denmark: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Egypt: Research Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - England: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - England: Doctors, undated, 1936, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - England: Nurses, undated, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - England: Barnett, Monica M. Milward, 1938, 1969-1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - England: Barnett, Monica M. Milward: Spanish Civil War Diary (transcription), 1938, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - England: Bates, Winifred and Ralph, undated, 1937-1939, 1969-1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - England: Bell, Elaine, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - England: Bird, Doris, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - England: Brown, Helen, undated, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - England: Bury, Henry Saunders, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - England: Clark, Sybil, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - England: Cochrane, Archibald Leman, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - England: Crispi, Walter, undated, 1937, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - England: Crome, Leonard, 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - England: Darton, Patience, undated, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - England: Deane, Christina, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - England: Green, Nan Farrow, 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - England: Guest, Angela, undated, 1937, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - England: Hibbert, Phyllis, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - England: LeVann, Leonard J., undated, 1972-1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - England: Murray, Anne, 1938, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - England: Phelps, Penny, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - England: Phillips, Wogan (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - England: Saxton, Reginald, undated, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - England: Silverthorne, Thora, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - England: Sinclair-Loutit, Kenneth, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - England: Slater, Mary Elisabeth, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - England: Tudor Hart, Alexander, undated, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - England: Young, George, 1937, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - France: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - France: Doctors, undated, 1938, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - France: Nurses, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - France: Bonnet, Luis, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - France: Bré, Fanny, 1965-1983 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - France: Chaimowiez, Monique, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - France: Chretien, Henri, undated, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - France: Gosset, Louise, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - France: Kestenberg, Jean J., undated, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - France: Rappaport, Ruth and Elie, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - France: Tenin, Juliette, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Germany: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Germany: Doctors and Nurses, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Germany: Becker, Rolf, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Germany: Bodek, Kathe, undated, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Germany: Cohn, Ernst (a.k.a. Heinrich Kent) and Edith Kent Marcuse, undated, 1939-1942, 1972-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Germany: Coutelle, Carl, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Germany: Ewert, Olla, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Germany: Glaser, Wilhelm and Erika Glaser Wallach, undated, 1970-1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Germany: Gundelach, Gustav, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Germany: Kosterlitz, Kurt, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9A)
  - Germany: Liebert, Josephine, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Germany: Littwack, Eva, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Germany: Mayer, Ursula Amann, undated, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Germany: Muller, Meta, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Germany: Stemmler, Antonia, 1971, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Holland: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1936-1939, 1969-1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Holland: Doctors and Nurses, undated, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Holland: deVries, Gertrud (a.k.a Van Reemst), 1972-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Holland: Hulleman, Katrijn (Tryn), 1937-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Holland: Maas, Johana (Jopie), undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Holland: Maas, Johana (Jopie), 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Holland: Maas, Johana (Jopie), 1971-1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Hungary: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1966-1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Hungary: Beer, Imre (a.k.a. Oscar Goryan), undated, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hungary: Haraszti, Istvan, 1970-1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Hungary: Révecz, Annamarija (a.k.a. Anna Maria Basch), 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - India: Research Notes, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ireland: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1936, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Ireland: O'Reilly, John Patrick, undated, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Ireland: O'Reilly, John Patrick: Notes from Villa Paz Hospital, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Italy: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Japan: Research Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Latvia: Research Notes, 1966, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Lithuania: Research Notes and Articles, undated, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Mexico: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Mexico: Bingham di Urquidi, Mary: Articles and Correspondence, undated, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Mexico: Bingham di Urquidi, Mary: Mercy in Madrid(typescript), pp. 1-125, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Mexico: Bingham di Urquidi, Mary: Mercy in Madrid(typescript), pp. 126-225, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Mexico: Bingham di Urquidi, Mary: Mercy in Madrid(typescript), pp. 226-320, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Mexico: Bingham di Urquidi, Mary: Mercy in Madrid(typescript), pp. 321-389 (page 388 missing), undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - New Zealand, undated, 1937, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - New Zealand: Jolly, Douglas, undated, 1970-1983 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Norway: General Correspondence and Research Notes, undated, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Palestine: Research Notes, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Peru: General Correspondence and Research Notes, undated, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Peru: Bauman, Gerold Gino (Researcher), 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Poland: General Correspondence and Research Notes, undated, 1968-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Poland: Doctors, undated, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Poland: Nurses, undated, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Poland: Beer, Zygfryd, undated, 1976-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Poland: Domanski, Mieczyslaw (a.k.a. Dubois), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Poland: Ersler, Gabriel, undated, 1971-1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Poland: Flato, Stanislaw, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Poland: Jungerman, Wolf (a.k.a. Wolf Jungery), 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Poland: Kofler, Adolf, 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Poland: Kraus, David, undated, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Poland: Lewin, Dorota, 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Poland: Lorska, Dorota (a.k.a. Dora Kleinova), undated, 1965, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Poland: Namiot Hollender, Liza, undated, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Poland: Namiot Hollender, Liza, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Puerto Rico: General Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Romania: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Romania: Doctors, undated, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Romania: Nurses, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Romania: Jancu, David, undated, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Romania: Perelmann, Michel, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Soviet Union: General Correspondence and Research, 1939-1940, 1969-1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Spain: General Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Spain: Doctors, undated, 1937-1952, 1971-1977 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Spain: Nurses, undated, 1940-1941, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Spain: Bastos Ansart, Manuel, undated, 1940, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Spain: Broggi Vallés, Moisés, undated, 1938, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Spain: Colon Gomez, Julio, undated, 1939, 1971-1977 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Spain: Folch Pi, Alberto, undated, 1937-1943, 1971-1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Spain: Gomez Ulla, Mariano, undated, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Spain: Harcourt Got, Joaquin d', undated, 1936, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Spain: Harcourt Got, Joaquin d': Medical Writings, 1935-1947 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Spain: Estellés Salarich, José, undated, 1937, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Spain: Marti-Ibanez, Félix, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Spain: Marti- Ibanez, Félix: Writings, 1964-1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Spain: Merino Hernandéz, Wenceslao, undated, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Spain: Montseny, Federica, undated; 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 39a)
  - Spain: Perez, Aurelio, Ambulance Driver (lengthy memoir), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Spain: Perez-Elias, Dr., undated, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 40A)
  - Spain: Planelles Ripoll, Juan, undated, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Spain: Puche Alvarez, José, undated, 1938-1945, 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Spain: Quemada, Luis, undated, 1937, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Spain: Sanmarti Falguera, Enrique, undated, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Spain: Somolinos D'Ardois, German, 1963, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Spain: Trueta, José, undated, 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Spain: Trueta, José: Writings related to medical treatment in the Spanish Civil War, 1936, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Sweden: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1971-1979 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Sweden: Doctors, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Sweden: Eriksson, Per, 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Switzerland: General Correspondence and Research, undated, 1939, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - United States: General Correspondence and Research Notes, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - United States: Ambulance Drivers and Chauffeurs, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - United States: Doctors, undated, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - United States: Lab Technicians, Pharmacists, Engineers and Clerks, undated, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - United States: Nurses, undated, 1937-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - United States: Nurses Married in Spain, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - United States: Personnel Arrested in Valencia (Byrne, Albert; Duncan, Cleo; Erickson, Thelma; Temple, Leonora), 1938, 1971-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - United States: Political Commissar Questionnaire, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - United States: Ranks, Name List with Ranks, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - United States: Abramson, Rose, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - United States: Alvarez, Leonardo, undated, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - United States: Andell, Evelyn, 1937-1938, 1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - United States: Barsky, Edward, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - United States: Barsky, Edward: Clippings, 1947-1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - United States: Barsky, Edward: Correspondence and Notes, 1967-1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - United States: Barsky, Edward: Interview, Jan 1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - United States: Barsky, Edward: Research Photocopies, 1936-1950 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - United States: Berkowitz, Grace, undated, 1937, 1969-1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - United States: Bissel, Franklin, undated, 1937, 1968-1975 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - United States: Bloom, Nathan, undated, 1935-1937, 1970- 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - United States: Briggs, Judson, undated, 1938-1951, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - United States: Brisker, Luba: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1938-1938, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - United States: Brisker, Luba: Correspondence, 1972-1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - United States: Bruzzichesi, Ave: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1938-1939, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - United States: Bruzzichesi, Ave: Correspondence to Leo Eloesser (copies and originals), 1938-1940 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - United States: Busch, Irving, undated, 1937-1939, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - United States: Busch, Irving (letter from Sybil Clark), ca.1937 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - United States: Byrne, Albert, undated, 1970-1984 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - United States: Byrne, Albert: Arrest in Spain, 1938, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - United States: Byrne, Albert: Correspondence, undated, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - United States: Byrne, Albert: Correspondence, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - United States: Byrne, Albert: Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - United States: Caldwell, Donald (Donn) Mansfield, 1937, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - United States: Carter, Council (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1938-1939, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - United States: Cessick, John (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1936-1937, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - United States: Chadwick, Selma, undated, 1938-1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - United States: Chodoff, Richard Joseph and Eleanor Dean, 1937, 1968-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - United States: Cohn, Lewis I., 1938, 1969-1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - United States: Cross, Christopher (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1937, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - United States: Davidow, Ruth: Carnet Militar and Autograph Book (photocopies), 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - United States: Davidow, Ruth: Correspondence and Questionnaire, undated, 1968-1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - United States: Davidow, Ruth: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1939, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - United States: Devetskoe, Charles (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1937-1939, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini (a.k.a. Lini Fuhr): Articles and Clippings, 1937-1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Correspondence (DeVries to FM), undated, 1946, 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Correspondence (to DeVries from friends and relatives), undated, 1957, 1965-1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Correspondence (to DeVries from Johanna "Jopie" Maas), 1970-1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Correspondence (to FM from DeVries friends and relatives), 1969-1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Correspondence: Spanish Civil War (originals and copies), 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Death, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Mexico, undated, 1965-1976 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Speaking Tour, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Questionnaire and Research Materials, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1980 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Writings: Diary (typescript with annotations and notes), 1937, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Writings: "March of Life, The", undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Writings: "Up from the Cellar" (Typescript), pp. 1-110, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Writings: "Up from the Cellar" (Typescript), pp. 111-212, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - United States: DeVries, Lini: Writings: "Up from the Cellar" (Typescript), pp. 213-263, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - United States: Dhaga, Jose: Correspondence, undated, 1975-1984 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - United States: Dhaga, Jose: Questionnaire and Research, undated, 1938, 1967-1976 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - United States: Dhaga, Jose: Spanish Civil War: Correspondence, Documents, Medical Bureau Ephemera, undated, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - United States: Dowowa, Arnold, 1937-1939, 1969-1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - United States: Draper, George T., undated, 1938, 1968-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - United States: Duncan, Cleo Cannon, undated, 1938, 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - United States: Duncan, Cleo Cannon: Correspondence (Letter to Dr. Elloesser), 1937 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - United States: Dyer, May Edythe, 1937-1938, 1968-1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - United States: Eloesser, Leo: Articles and Clippings, 1936-1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - United States: Eloesser, Leo: Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - United States: Eloesser, Leo: Ephemera: leaflets, tickets, medical forms, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - United States: Eloesser, Leo: Eulogy for a Free Spirit(excerpt of biography by Harris Shumacker), 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - United States: Eloesser, Leo: FM Correspondence with Joyce Eloesser and Research Notes, 1969-1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - United States: Eloesser, Leo: Research Materials (photocopies), 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - United States: Eloesser, Leo: Spanish Civil War Correspondence and Dispatches, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - United States: Epstein, Ruth, 1937-1938, 1969-1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - United States: Erickson, Thelma: Correspondence, 1969-1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - United States: Erickson, Thelma: Identity papers, Oceanliner ticket, Marriage License (photocopies), 1938 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - United States: Erickson, Thelma: Questionnaire and Research Notes, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - United States: Erickson, Thelma: Research Photocopies and Articles, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - United States: Erickson, Thelma: Spanish Civil War Correspondence (originals and photocopies), 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - United States: Ettleson, Abraham, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1972 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - United States: Ettleson, Dora, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1975 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - United States: Ferreiro Latrader, Ceasar (Ambulance Driver), undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - United States: Ferwerda, Ena, undated, 1937, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - United States: Flett, Harold, undated, 1937, 1969-1975 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - United States: Fontaine Mardfin, Dorothy: Correspondence, undated, 1937-1946, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - United States: Fontaine Mardfin, Dorothy: Correspondence, 1971-1979 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - United States: Fontaine Mardfin, Dorothy: Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - United States: Fontaine Mardfin, Dorothy: Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - United States: Fontaine Mardfin, Dorothy: Correspondence: Speaking Tour (Research photocopies), 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - United States: Fontaine Mardfin, Dorothy: Passport: Correspondence (Research Photocopies), 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - United States: Fontaine Mardfin, Dorothy: Questionaire, Research Notes and Clippings, 1969-1979 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - United States: Franklin, Samuel N., undated, 1971-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - United States: Franklin, Samuel N.: Leaflets, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - United States: Freed, Rose, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - United States: Freeman, Helen: Clipping, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - United States: Freeman, Helen: Correspondence (including copy of lengthy unsigned letter, probably FM to HF), undated, 1944-1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - United States: Freeman, Helen: Correspondence, 1969-1983 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - United States: Freeman, Helen: Questionnaire and Research Notes and photocopies, undated, 1937-1939, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - United States: Fried, Marcus, 1937-1938, 1968-1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - United States: Friedman Abraham, Irving: Questionnaire and Research Materials, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - United States: Friedman, Abraham Irving: Clippings, undated, 1937-1938, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - United States: Goland, Philip P., 1937-1938, 1969-1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - United States: Goldberg, Alex (Ambulance Driver), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - United States: Goldblatt, Sana, 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - United States: Goldblatt, Sana: Correspondence, undated, 1948-1959 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - United States: Goldblatt, Sana: Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - United States: Goldblatt, Sana: Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - United States: Goldblatt, Sana: Questionnaire and Research Notes, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - United States: Goldin Spiegel, Irene, 1938-1939, 1968-1979 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - United States: Goldstein, Jack J., undated, 1937-1939, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - United States: Golub, Fanny, 1937-1938, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - United States: Gomez, Sebastian (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1941-1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - United States: Gomez, Sebastian (Ambulance Driver): Spanish Civil War Correspondence and Documents, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - United States: Gonzales, Joseó (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - United States: Graeber, Kenneth (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - United States: Grunblatt, Jacques (a.k.a. Jacob), undated, 1938, 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Carnet Militar, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Clippings, 1937-1939, 1944, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence from Paris and Spain, Oct 1937-Sep 1938 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence, undated, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Passenger List ("Veendam"), Sep 3, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Questionnaires, 1938, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1939, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - United States: Guzman, Jaime de, 1937-1940, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Correspondence from Spain, Mar 1938-Dec 1938 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Correspondence, 1967-1988 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Questionnaire and Writings, undated, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Correspondence, undated, 1969-1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Correspondence from Hospital Frederica Montceny (Murcia), 1937 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Questionnaire, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - United States: Hartzman, Jack (Ambulance Driver), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - United States: Harvan, Rose, undated, 1937-1941, 1968-1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - United States: Hayes, Thomas (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1937-1938, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - United States: Henderson, Florence Elizabeth (Bessie), 1937-1938, 1968-1975 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - United States: Henderson, Florence Elizabeth (Bessie): Passenger List and Menu ("Veendam"), Nov 7, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 9)